leonardo

muñoz

leomunoz.me

leonardomr1@gmail.com

(+52) 1-55-3655-5990

in leomunozr

aleomunozr

PROFILE

I'm a developer based in wonderful Mexico City.

I create web apps with a focus on a smooth user experience and implementation of best coding practices.

I'm constantly learning new technologies to stay relevant and bring the best of engineering and innovation together.

SKILLS

- LINUX
- Javascript
- HTML5
- SASS
- ES6
- React
- Redux
- Angular
- Webpack
- Gulp
- Node
- Scripting

EXPERIENCE

Globant Mexico / Sourceability

Lead Angular developer • October 2018 - January 2019

- Improved user experience by redesigning widgets to be interactive and facilitate the user to manipulate data and rearrange layouts.
- Reduced app's initial loading time by better bootstrapping Angular and better managing DOM manipulation.
- Followed Scrum methodology.

Globant Mexico / ZapLabs

Javascript developer • September 2017 - October 2018

- Developed web tools to consolidate the administration of the brand's subsidiaries' blogs under a single site.
- Developed new features for blogs using plain Javascript and ES6.
- Followed Kanban methodology.

Globant Mexico / DWA Nova

React developer • September 2016 - August 2017

- Developed a cross-platform desktop app for managing Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator assets using frontend technologies.
- Created desktop app with React + Redux $\,$ and Electron, and Adobe plugin with HTML/Javascript $\,$
- Integrated with Node server for local file storage through sockets with WebSockets and socket.io.
- Unit tests done with Mocha, Chai, Sinon and Enzyme.

Globant Mexico / United Airlines

AngularJS Developer • November 2015 - September 2016

- Developed a control panel to administrate personnel and daily tasks using AngularJS, ES6 and SASS.
- Created widgets with a focus on reusability to share components among projects.
- Created scripts to build environment and scaffold components using Webpack and Gulp.
- Followed Scrum methodology.

Indigo Smart Software Development

.NET Developer • August 2015 - November 2015

- Designed and created an API for processing payments in an e-commerce application using .NFT.
- Maintenance of existing RESTful web services of a flight ticket booking application

UNAM-SPF

Full Stack developer • June 2014 – July 2015

- Developed an app for payment services in a government agency.
- Created UI following an MVVM pattern with KnockoutJS, Lodash and HTML5.
- Implemented digital signature process for documents using .NET Crypto API.

KMMX

Instructor • May - September 2014, January 2015, July 2015

- Taught courses about HTML5 APIs and features, AJAX with PHP and Java Fundamentals to students ranging from beginners to IT specialists.

EDUCATION

Diplomate Course

National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)

Embedded Linux

May - November 2015

Bachelor's Degree

National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)

Electrical – Electronic Engineering

2007 - 2013